Kostadis Roussos: The high tower loomed ahead of them, and with it, the final confrontation.
Grygum: Mmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thorin: The final confrontation.
Grygum: Let's see. So, if we're gonna get into the tower, do we have both keys now?
Kostadis Roussos: You have one of the two keys. We have one of the two keys. LA was probably there, waiting for Moziqodo to show up.
Grygum: Okay, so he probably has the other one, and he's probably waiting for us, so… or for… for somebody.
Grygum: Okay.
Grygum: Well, I suspect this is gonna be a fight. Let me see whether there's…
Daz: I agree.
Grygum: I have anything to prepare.
Daz: Have we rested? We have not rested, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, you have not rested.
Grygum: Do we have time for it?
Kostadis Roussos: You have a time for… well, you can…
Kostadis Roussos: You don't know if you have time or you don't have time, but you can always take a short rest.
Thorin: Let's do a short rest, at least.
Daz: Yeah, because I'm at 9 hit points, so I think a short rest would be.
Grygum: Oh.
Thorin: Oh, I'm at full hit points, so…
Grygum: I could use a short rest.
Thorin: Yeah, it sounds like you being at 9 is a you problem, but…
Thorin: I'm kidding.
Daz: Alright, I have completed my short rest.
Daz: Wait, it didn't… It didn't heal me.
Grygum: Yeah, I don't always under… the… the…
Grygum: DnD Beyond interface, I don't understand it.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that one is just…
Grygum: Here, I'll, I'll roll it by hand.
Daz: I still didn't do it.
Daz: It's, like, broken.
Kostadis Roussos: It's like this weird… I can't figure it out.
Daz: So if I say I'm doing a short rest, and I say I want to take… oh, I have to roll this.
Thorin: So my 2 hit with Dawnbringer is now plus 10, he don't…
Kostadis Roussos: Don't miss…
Thorin: Yes. Yeah, she? He?
Kostadis Roussos: She…
Thorin: They don't miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Shit!
Kostadis Roussos: You know, Dawnbringer… you and Dawnbringer need to sort that out. Like, I'm sorry.
Thorin: I mean, you know, whatevs.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but you guys need to, you guys need to tell us what you guys want her to be known.
Thorin: Bring a she. Dawnbringer is a she. I had a girlfriend in high school named Dawn. God help me.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Daz: That's not right. I told it to roll a whole bunch of dice. How come I only rolled one?
Daz: You know what? I'm just gonna roll for everything, and I'm gonna assume I got enough, that I got my 45 that I needed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: Whatever.
Daz: I think that works.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you take a moment to rest.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So Tadric hands you over the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Tans you over the key,
Thorin: We've got one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Then, as he hands it over to Key, it says, I held it all night, and I didn't know what it was. Now that I know what it is, I'm not giving it to you and going to bed. He's offering to come along with you.
Grygum: We, I, I assure him that, that, that, he, he could be helpful, but it's also dangerous.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I faced… I faced Moziqodo! I faced the full… I… no, I, I, I will… he's… he's definitely suffering from a desperate desire to be heroic.
Grygum: Well, come along. I do have, resurrection magic if worst comes to worst.
Kostadis Roussos: If Daral was here, he says, but, but what about me?
Grygum: Well, I didn't have it then.
Kostadis Roussos: Perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: Just as you're standing there, the acoustics deliver a sound from far off in the key.
Kostadis Roussos: The endless chant has stopped. Now, one of the most important things about Candlekeep, just so you guys know, is that there's this endless chant of the prophecies.
Grygum: Was this ever mentioned? I don't remember this.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm sorry, if I never mentioned it, it was one…
Daz: I mentioned on the first day that we were there, maybe. Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: They continuously read the prophecies, and every time a prophecy comes true.
Kostadis Roussos: They delete the prophecy and keep repeating, right?
Grygum: So, if Grygum is anything like me, then, I haven't noticed it for, like, the last 3 days anyway. Once it stops, I notice that it stopped.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but you also notice it because
Kostadis Roussos: Tadric is kind of like…
Kostadis Roussos: stunned. Like, this is, like, this never happens.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so now you have to decide. So…
Kostadis Roussos: Tadric looks at you and says.
Kostadis Roussos: Sylvira… someone needs to tell Sylvira that her son is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: He's looking at the four of you, like…
Grygum: Oh, well, Ugh.
Kostadis Roussos: There's this awkward silence as the four of you look at her, right?
Grygum: It might best be someone who knows Sylvira.
Kostadis Roussos: Passing the buck.
Grygum: I mean…
Daz: Well, not just…
Grygum: bonus.
Grygum: Go ahead.
Daz: No.
Daz: They want to be empathetic, and, like, they would have the best understanding of how to be the empathetic
Daz: To her, as they explain this unfortunate news.
Daz: And it's passing the book.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's passing the buck, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Tadric, looks at the four of you, so…
Kostadis Roussos: So you're just gonna say, you know what, maybe later, we gotta go deal with A'lai Aivenmore, just… that's…
Grygum: I'm happy to, you know, like, back you up, but… I'll go with you.
Kostadis Roussos: It's okay, Daz, you don't have to go, it's fine. I just want to make sure that, you know, Tadric kind of drops that bomb here.
Grygum: Got it.
Daz: There you go.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, alright, you guys decide. Sometimes, sometimes…
Daz: We'll take care of it later.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a later kind of problem, right?
Daz: Yeah, it's a later… it's a later…
Daz: Emerald Vanguard, or whatever we're calling ourselves these days.
Grygum: purple.
Kostadis Roussos: Ember Grapple. You're the Ember Grapple, right? No rela- no, no, no causal or not…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, nothing, no, no, no relationship between… The, the two. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: So you've decided to… you'll go after the, you'll go after the High Tower to go, to go see what's,
Kostadis Roussos: All right. As you… so you… so… so, Tadric, fortunately, knows where the High Tower is, and he, will… will take you towards there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: As you're.
Grygum: I was going to… I was going to see if I wanted to prepare any… spells…
Grygum: Let me see here…
Grygum: Yeah, I will, I will cast…
Grygum: I'll cast Bless on, the…
Grygum: The three of us who are, who are, who are here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay. That's it. That is not a bad decision. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: As you approach… As you approach the… as you head towards the walkway.
Kostadis Roussos: You notice a dead watcher.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you guys go on a… up ahead? Do you want to go check out what's happened to him?
Daz: Watcher.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's the name of the guards of Candlekeep.
Daz: Does he… does it… does he look, like, conspicuously out of place, or that maybe he has some info?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he looks dead from an arrow.
Daz: Oh, dead! When you said dead.
Grygum: Oh, okay.
Grygum: You thought he… you thought he looked like Daz?
Daz: So the arrow is out of place, maybe.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, the arrow was out of…
Kostadis Roussos: You, you look at the… so, do you want to investigate him, or keep going?
Daz: Yeah, I think we spend a little bit of time investigating. My passive investigation's now 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright,
Daz: I don't know how that happened, but that's… Yeah, I…
Grygum: I, I don't…
Kostadis Roussos: For the record, with a passive investigation of 24,
Kostadis Roussos: You're basically Sherlock Holmes at this point.
Daz: How did that happen?
Daz: Is that just from going up to level 9?
Kostadis Roussos: Now I'm curious, man.
Thorin: I mean, this is one of the problems with DnD Beyond, is you're like, here's a number, how did we get that number? I don't know, sometimes it tells you, sometimes it doesn't.
Kostadis Roussos: We're gonna complain about the user experience of this program?
Daz: No, no, I'm not complaining now.
Daz: 24, that's pretty cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: Oh, is… my intelligence is… 20?
Grygum: That would do it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I would do it.
Daz: Oh, did I actually get a stat, and I didn't realize it, and it just defaulted to intelligence?
Grygum: Could be.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Grygum: But I don't think you get that at level 9. That would be…
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you know, your passive investigation.
Daz: It's 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, yes, yes, the way… okay, so here's how it works. So, you see your investigation, which is a 9?
Daz: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And you see the plus 5 from intelligence?
Daz: Yes, those two add together, get plus 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Passive and get… your passive number is equal to 10 plus.
Daz: Those two.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, your investigation is a plus 9.
Kostadis Roussos: Part of… and you have advantage when you roll.
Daz: Yes.
Daz: So… I can figure shit out.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, I, I, you, you've…
Daz: The rest of us don't even have to.
Grygum: I tried.
Daz: It's like that Sherlock Holmes stuff where you can see, like, he… he sees that the cabbie didn't shave the back of his neck, and so he knows that his wife is dead. Yes. Because his wife would have told him that the back of his neck needed a shave, but…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yeah, yeah, basically. Yeah, basically, we're, you know, we're basically at that level of investigation at 24.
Daz: Cool, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? You walk into a room, you see something, and you go, aha.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Daz: So, what do I aha about the arrow-ridden guard?
Kostadis Roussos: You… aha! Right, I'm just, like, going… right, so now it's kind of like… Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: It's, it's… the crossbow bolt, you immediately recognize the crossbow bolt's fletching as not being from the area.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and not be consistent with the crossbow bolts of the other… that are used by the watchers, which you had noticed as you had walked into the castle, so clearly indicating that whoever fired this arrow came from outside of the Candlekeep.
Daz: Okay, so, and knowing what we know, then that probably means it's outside actors that are up to all this mischief.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yes, okay.
Grygum: How old… It was fired from outside? Are we on a wall? Was it fired from below?
Kostadis Roussos: So, it's on a walkway.
Kostadis Roussos: So, so he looks as if he was shot from…
Kostadis Roussos: So, let me see if I can…
Grygum: The, this…
Kostadis Roussos: I need to draw. Okay. This is gonna… this is going to… this… this will not work well if I don't draw, because I will get it wrong, because my spatial reasoning is not like my wife's.
Kostadis Roussos: Natasha's spatial reasoning is kind of creepy.
Kostadis Roussos: Like…
Kostadis Roussos: she can't do 3D, but, like, if I draw… if she… she can navigate herself in an area where she's never been once.
Thorin: No, my wife can't do 3D, but if you ask her, hey, will these leftovers fit in this thing, she's always right. Her, like, volume estimation is amazing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Natasha's, of 2D spatial reasoning is kind of crazy.
Kostadis Roussos: Damn.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see my games, let me just get to the right game.
Kostadis Roussos: Ha!
Kostadis Roussos: Technology. Why does technology exist? You know why it exists? To irritate me.
Kostadis Roussos: I've told you the whole why I hate technology. It's because there's always some PM, and there's always some engineering manager, and there's always some engineer, and there's always someone in QA, and there's always somebody in UX, and there's this thing that would make everybody's… the customer's life better, but engineering doesn't want to work on it, the engineering manager doesn't want to deal with
Kostadis Roussos: convincing people the PM doesn't think it's going to make more money, the UX guy has this grand vision that they want to implement.
Kostadis Roussos: The QA person explains that it's gonna… that the automation of it is gonna take forever, and customer support says there's a workaround.
Grygum: Computers were a mistake, basically.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and so as a result, they all turn to him and say, yeah! And what they don't realize is he loves the workaround because it makes him the most valuable person in the room.
Kostadis Roussos: Because he gets to drive up his customer sat numbers by saying, this was a customer interaction that customer support nailed.
Grygum: Everybody's gotta have a reason to be there.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and that is why software sucks. I should…
Kostadis Roussos: I just want… and then I said this to a bunch of people in a meeting, and I kid you not, by the end of the meeting, we had made that decision.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, seriously?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm gonna let you see something.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the way to think about it is that… okay, I'll do it this way.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So… you're…
Kostadis Roussos: This, can you guys see? You should be able to see me drawing that right now, yeah?
Grygum: I see a gray line.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, okay. So this is a walkway.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And you guys are coming down the walkway.
Kostadis Roussos: And as you are coming down the walkway, you see a dead watcher.
Thorin: Am I supposed to see just sort of gray lines and squares, or is there something… Yeah, yeah, that's it. Okay, okay, yeah.
Thorin: Just wanna make sure I'm not missing anything here.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you're not missing anything. Alright, so this is the walkway.
Grygum: Okay, are we indoors?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you're indoors, so there's a…
Grygum: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so you came up some stairs.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you, you climbed up some stairs.
Grygum: It's quite unusual for someone to be killed with an arrow indoors.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and so what you've concluded is that
Kostadis Roussos: The bad guys went up the same stairs.
Grygum: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Killed him, and kept advancing forward.
Grygum: The arrow was shot from the direction that we're coming from? Yep. Yes. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so I'll… just to make this, totally obvious, this party over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Tadric goes over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just make… Let's send this to the map layer, so that I don't map. Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: This is the direction everybody's going. Consider this notional, not necessarily… representational, to give you guys sort of a visual understanding of what's going on.
Daz: Okay.
Grygum: Got it. So, I'm not, like, a medical expert or anything, but… oh, well, actually, I am. I have plus 5 medicine. How long ago do I think he was shot?
Kostadis Roussos: Not very long. Like, within the last half hour.
Grygum: Okay, so, let's, let's look out for somebody with a boat.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you, you can, alright. So, you, I presume you're now going to be walking a little bit more cautiously, and not, you know, trying to make sure that… preparing for… preparing for anything is kind of the situation, right?
Grygum: Cautiously, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you arrive at, the skyscraping lobby.
Kostadis Roussos: And there are two raiders looting the lobby, bagging books from a written manifest.
Grygum: Skyscraping?
Kostadis Roussos: So that's the name of the lobby. So if we go back to here, right.
Kostadis Roussos: You arrive at the lobby.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just draw this in a different color.
Kostadis Roussos: This is the lobby.
Grygum: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Lobby of High Tower.
Grygum: Oh, okay, it's the… the… Yes. Entrance.
Grygum: Basically.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Grygum: Sour. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And inside here, there are two raters who are careful… reading a manifest and pulling books.
Grygum: I suppose they haven't noticed us yet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, they haven't noticed you yet.
Grygum: When you say Raiders… What do they…
Grygum: Alice, tell me a little about them.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there are guys in equipment,
Kostadis Roussos: They're… they've got swords, they definitely… you look at them and you realize some of their swords have blood, right?
Grygum: Okay, and probably one of them has a bow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, actually, that's the thing you notice, that you don't… nobody does have a boat. What you do here, though, is up the stairs.
Kostadis Roussos: That,
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see… Just make sure I got this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, as you look inside.
Kostadis Roussos: So there's the… there's the guard here, there's a couple of guards, and then on the second floor of the landing is a wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: Whom you recognize.
Grygum: Wait, this was a… this is somebody we can see from the lobby, or are we past.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, I'm about to explain.
Grygum: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Just wanted to… Give me a second.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: So you… so as you… you arrive over… so let's see here we go. I'll put him on the… let's put him on the right layer, change layer…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you guys arrive at the lobby, Right?
Kostadis Roussos: And inside of the lobby, of the High Tower, so you're kind of at the…
Kostadis Roussos: Near the top of this High Tower, you see… You see two guards.
Kostadis Roussos: do, how do I call it?
Kostadis Roussos: It's just stupid.
Kostadis Roussos: And there are two people sort of, like, pulling books and trying to, like, grab stuff from a sort of a list, and then standing on the second floor of the landing is a wizard whom you recognize as A'lai Aivenmore.
Grygum: Oh. This is the guy who has the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, this is the guy who has the key.
Grygum: Did he need to use the key to get into the lobby?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he needed the key to get through the second door.
Kostadis Roussos: He's… Perfect.
Grygum: He is through the second door?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's not through the second door.
Grygum: Oh, okay, so we have the other key, and presumably his does.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so I'm gonna, I'm gonna just draw that second door so that you guys, know that. So he's like.
Daz: So, it's safe to assume that one of these people that's in front of us is one of the people that shot the guard.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, I should have made… that was… that was my mistake, yes, one of them does have… yes, one of them does have a bow, sorry, oh my god.
Grygum: Okay, well that clears up a mystery. Good.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes. So, A'lai Aivenmore is sort of sitting over there, he's waiting over there. You guys see what's going on, but you haven't yet marched in, so I'm going to give you an opportunity to decide what you want to do.
Daz: Hmm.
Grygum: I'm more worried about the wizard than, about these raiders. We can… we're probably more than a match for them.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, just to put things in perspective, the A'lai Aivenmore Is a pretty powerful wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: So keep that in mind.
Kostadis Roussos: But, like all powerful wizards, he's also more obsessed with staying alive than he is fighting to the death.
Grygum: Just like dragons.
Kostadis Roussos: S.
Thorin: So is he the one with the third eye?
Kostadis Roussos: He's… what do you mean, the third eye? The, the, the, he's the… the, the, the…
Thorin: The icons.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, the one… he's the… let me just make sure that you… I realized I wrote the name, but I didn't, set it here. You should be able to see him now, yeah?
Thorin: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so yes.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a really awkward picture, because he's supposed to look like a drow wizard, but, you know…
Grygum: He looks a little bit like a…
Grygum: Hindu Clown or something? I don't know. One thing we could do, guys, is try to eliminate the raiders so that we can focus on a lie, so I could, you know, cast some kind of spell to…
Grygum: Try to get them in, one,
Grygum: You know, one… one… one spell casting.
Grygum: Because I suspect that we just need to fight them and kill them.
Daz: How tall is the wizard?
Grygum: He wasn't expecting that question.
Kostadis Roussos: He's, yeah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Kostadis Roussos: Can we say between 5 feet and 6 feet? Does it need a specific number?
Daz: Now, just less or more… more or less than 5 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Between 5 and 6 feet.
Grygum: Okay.
Daz: human.
Grygum: light, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's not under 5 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: I had a plan for maybe, boxing, literally boxing the, Wizard in while we took care of the other guys, just to make sure we were clear.
Daz: But I think I'll wait on that.
Daz: Maybe use it for something else.
Daz: Yeah, I like the plan of just, like, knocking down the…
Daz: knock down the DPS towards us by getting the two weaker guys out of the way.
Grygum: Excellent.
Daz: By the way, that Rogue Builder thing you sent me is pretty cool. I did load it, and it's working fine in my browser.
Kostadis Roussos: Great, great, great, great.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I got really annoyed, and so, I was… I've been working and trying to… what's the word I'm looking for?
Kostadis Roussos: trying to see what I can do with the stupider AMI models, and so one of the things I did was use it to create those things.
Kostadis Roussos: it taught me that, you know, stupid AI models have learned from really stupid programmers who don't under… and so I had to beat it with a stick to tell it to stop trying to use regex to parse HTTP.
Grygum: Ugh.
Thorin: For your HTML, you mean?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, HTML. Oh my god! Like, it kept trying to do that. I said, don't do that! Finally, I was like, don't do that! But you see, I'm so used to talking to junior engineers that I would say, like, please don't do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you not do that? I really want you to not do that. So, hold on, hold on. So finally, I said, can you write out the rule? And the rule was like, Don't ever do that! If you do that, you're doing something wrong!
Thorin: I've been finding that I've been getting into these, like, rat holes with the agent, where it's like.
Thorin: We'll start being super pedantic about stuff, and, like, instead of saying, why are we being so pedantic, this is stupid.
Thorin: I'll just continue to go down. And so you end up with, like, the most bulletproof, like, well-specified bash script you've ever seen, right? And at some point, I just have to, like, reel the thing back in and be like, we're being dumb here, this shouldn't be this hard. What the hell are you doing?
Thorin: But you have to be able to say to yourself that quality is a variable that I'm willing to turn… a dial I'm willing to turn, which is… which is hard to admit sometimes to yourself.
Grygum: Yes. Yes. Yes, it is.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, alright, so you want to take out the MOOCs? Alright, so let's just do the lot… then we will need a bit of a battle map here, so let me just,
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me just do this, make page.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so… I'll make it, I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: a tower.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see…
Kostadis Roussos: This is a pretty big tower.
Kostadis Roussos: There are some, some stairs over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, you're not seeing anything because I'm busily drawing.
Kostadis Roussos: I had a lot of things to do this week, so I didn't quite get all my maps done, so I apologize for that.
Daz: Oh, you're fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, I know, right?
Kostadis Roussos: It's, you know, my perfectionism is at play here.
Kostadis Roussos: Door over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And then there is a passageway over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And, okay, put some bookshelves over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, let me just see… Alright, so, A'lai.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh.
Kostadis Roussos: Drow mage.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's make… let's give them… let's… let's give them…
Kostadis Roussos: Let's make them look a little bit more authentic.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: I just… just so he looks a little bit more authentic.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, you're standing at the doorway, and the two guards are… there?
Kostadis Roussos: I just need a few more seconds, and there's some… there's some guards here. Give me one more second… I need to get the… the experience points out.
Grygum: Is the mage a lie?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. Let me just… let me just make sure that you guys have his name.
Kostadis Roussos: A'lai is currently standing in front of the door, waiting, thinking that Moziqodo is gonna run in at any point in time.
Grygum: Well, he's going to be pretty surprised by us, then.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Rice.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Let's put some… Give me one more second.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, there are… bugs.
Kostadis Roussos: Just to be clear, from where you are, you can't see everything in the room, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well, that's code for the GM warning you that there may be other people in the room you can't currently see.
Grygum: -Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: These guys are sort of, like, over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Pulling at the bookshelves.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: A'lai is sitting there at the table. He will… he will notice you the minute you walk in, just because he's, like, 10-15 feet above.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, these are stairs, intended to be stairs.
Grygum: I see him.
Daz: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so it's meant to be, like, 7-15 feet above.
Daz: What is the 15 number again? Oh, the 15.
Kostadis Roussos: It's meant to… yeah, it's meant to mean…
Thorin: Height, yeah.
Daz: Hype.
Daz: Cool, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Label Ghul says, is this where we use the flying spell?
Grygum: So, from the… with the spells that I've got, I could get both the thugs if… if I could get on, you know, at the end of a line of them.
Grygum: Or I could target any one of the people in the room. Like, they're not lined up for a good aim from the door, though.
Grygum: So, maybe I should… maybe I should aim for a lie instead, and then,
Grygum: And then other… the others… the rest of us can work on, the thugs?
Kostadis Roussos: Sounds good.
Grygum: What do you think, guys?
Thorin: So what was the plan again?
Grygum: target a lie instead of the thugs.
Thorin: Who? Me? You?
Grygum: me with my spell. I'm assuming that I can get a spell off before everybody realizes that we're there.
Thorin: Yeah, and I'm… I'm happy to sort of distract and try and kite the thugs a little bit.
Grygum: So, should I, should I try to cast a spell now? I was, I was thinking, Guiding Bolt, toward,
Grygum: Toward a lie.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you're gonna try guiding both towards the line?
Grygum: Yes.
Grygum: It has a 120-foot range, I assume that I'm within good range.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright,
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you gonna try to surprise him?
Grygum: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you're gonna have… alright, your stealth?
Grygum: Oh, stealth.
Grygum: 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm going to declare that he is most definitely not expecting you to show up.
Kostadis Roussos: So, he heard you running upstairs, so no particular thing, his passive perception… 16. No, he does not notice you. Alright, roll to hit.
Grygum: Okay, I, sort of jumped the gun on that, so I got a… I got a 13, which is lousy, oops.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but he is a wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: Not used to fighting. But he does have mage armor, so the spell does not affect him. A'lai… alright, so let's, okay, let's, roll for initiative. Like, the rest of you can, you can… the rest of you can try to execute a surprise maneuver as well.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, roll, let's roll for initiative as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, let me just bring up the initiative tracker.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Why do I have two Daz's? Daz, what did you roll?
Kostadis Roussos: 20 narrow.
Daz: It should be in there.
Kostadis Roussos: Why do I have two of you?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Thorin: Holy cow.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, guys, I got everybody's initiative very confused.
Thorin: Alright, I got 15.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you got 15?
Thorin: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: What's… what was your initiative? Zalthir's initiative is something ridiculous, obviously, because… Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: So that's how… that's how Zalthir rolls.
Kostadis Roussos: Huh.
Thorin: early, boom boom.
Kostadis Roussos: No, this isn't.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, plus 4.
Daz: Can I tell from… with my investigation, my passive perception and investigation from where we're at, can I make a guess as to the, intelligence
Daz: Saving throw modifier that the, wizard may have?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, because, he's a very powerful wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: His intelligence would be a very… so what are you gonna try to beat? His intelligence?
Daz: I was gonna try to cast something, and he would have to roll a 17 on an Intelligent save.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's got a… you… you would recon… you could see a powerful wizard from a mile away.
Grygum: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Daz: And I realize that anything that's an intelligent save with him is probably gonna be an automatic pass on his save.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, you know, I'm gonna… given, given your insane intelligence and investigation, plus 9.
Daz: It's plus 9.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Mine's plus 10, so now I… now I'm feeling like maybe he's not the smartest one around, you know?
Thorin: He's the smartest guy in the room.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what's your…
Daz: So he would have to roll an 8 or better.
Daz: Which is a better than 50% chance. Alright, I'll probably not cast that unless we get desperate.
Daz: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I'm sorry, Daz, I don't know what your initiative is.
Daz: 20. It's in the…
Kostadis Roussos: Notice.
Daz: Oh, it disappeared.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I know, because I ran into some technical difficulties.
Grygum: Mine's 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, I got yours. Don't worry about it.
Grygum: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And I need to get this guy here.
Kostadis Roussos: And then I need to roll, this guy here's initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's go to this guy… it's this initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: So, does that mean I get to go first?
Kostadis Roussos: 19.
Kostadis Roussos: Thanks.
Daz: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Daz: Hmm… Points to… I have 2 of those spells left. Good.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Daz: Whoa.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Daz, you go first.
Daz: Alright, I'm gonna cast Maximilian's Earthen Grasp on our friendly wizard to distract them while my party takes out the thugs.
Daz: So, he needs to make a strength save of 17 or higher.
Kostadis Roussos: What spell… you cast… you cast that spell, alright.
Grygum: I don't know this spell. What does it do?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's.
Daz: You said before.
Daz: 5-foot section of space, which I'm gonna choose right in front of him or to the side of him.
Daz: unoccupied space in the ground, within the range of the target. A medium hand made of compacted soil rises there and reaches one of the creatures you can see within 5 feet of it. The target must make a strength saving throw on a failed save. The target takes 2d6 bludgeoning damages and restrained for the spell's duration.
Grygum: Well, that's fun.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: And further actions, I can have it crush them.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, he's gonna try to counterspell it.
Daz: Oh, he can counterspell?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he can counterspell, you can counterspell.
Daz: Alright. How do you counterspell? I've never counterspelled.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, it says… don't you have the third level counterspell spell spell?
Daz: Did I train that one? Maybe I picked something else.
Grygum: Is this, like, the NOPE card in, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Daz: Maybe that's when I got Fireball.
Kostadis Roussos: Fireball, Counterspell, it's kind of one of those, it's… okay. So, what level of spell it is?
Daz: It is… Maximilian's Grasp.
Daz: It is a second level spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he ca- he uses his reaction to counterspell it. He's now been attacked. Alright, so A'lai…
Kostadis Roussos: Has now been attacked by Daz and by Grygum. Thorin.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll to see if you have, stealth to attack.
Thorin: So, stealth…
Kostadis Roussos: No, you do not.
Thorin: Wait, wait, wait.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay, right, sorry, sorry. Okay, so if I…
Thorin: I just want to look at, sort of, like, if I don't, then I'm gonna go after him, and I may, but, like…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I'm just trying to do with her, like, I have to see if anybody gets to attack before he does, that's what I'm trying to do, so if you didn't get…
Thorin: Well, I can do… so that was an ability check, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Thorin: It can do.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you also have Bless. Does Bless give you a plus one to… can you just…
Grygum: Oh, plus 1 die 4, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wait, plus one die 4?
Kostadis Roussos: You didn't roll your Bless advantage with your… when you did your, attack.
Grygum: Oh, gosh, well… Let me see what…
Kostadis Roussos: G4.
Grygum: Oops.
Kostadis Roussos: No, that's not enough.
Grygum: Well, I rolled it wrong.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Grygum: Yep, also not.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Thorin: Haha.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, that is, like, a 1 in 56 chance.
Grygum: I don't know, man. Not my day. On my original roll, I had a plus 9, and I got a 13, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Right, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Grygum, Thorin, do you have anything to improve your, your, your.
Kostadis Roussos: While you're doing that, I'm gonna go check, what,
Thorin: Okay, what do I have to get, do you think?
Kostadis Roussos: You would have to get a 14.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Thorin: bookkeep.
Thorin: And I'm at 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Thorin: Alright, so I'm gonna do… I'm gonna use one of my second wins… which I can do with…
Thorin: Tactical Mind, which lets me add a 1D10 to it.
Thorin: Fuck, motherfucker.
Grygum: Oh, man.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh my god!
Grygum: the, the one.
Thorin: Oh, wait, John.
Grygum: It's coming.
Thorin: The check still fails, the use of second wind isn't expanded, so I didn't lose anything by that. Okay.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thorin: But also, motherfucker.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Grygum, Zalthir, I guess Zalthir's up.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zalthir… does Zalthir, like, I'm so used to his other character… I had to get…
Thorin: 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me see… I just… I'm sorry, I don't know all of his abilities.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he have anything with speed, extra attack? No.
Kostadis Roussos: But he does have… he does have other abilities which allow him, which… which could be convenient.
Kostadis Roussos: However, Zalthir… And Glabbagool show up over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And… That… this is why everybody hates monks. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And they… he will now attack.
Grygum: Okay, my, I'm gonna try my speakers again, they were working badly earlier.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he does attacks once… Attacks a second time…
Kostadis Roussos: And what did… what were the… what was the attack rolls?
Kostadis Roussos: So he does 22 points of damage on, Alley.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so is it simply solid. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Shall we begin? Daz, you're up.
Daz: Alright, so what happened with my… with my cast? Did that work, or no?
Kostadis Roussos: Your cast, your spell, did not work.
Daz: Did it bounce back or anything? I'm fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you're fine, it just… it did not work.
Daz: It just didn't work. Okay, so now I get…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Now you get to, you get to,
Daz: Do I know how often he can do the counterspell thing?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, once per turn, so you can do it now… he could… you could probably do it,
Grygum: But it probably takes one of the spell slots, right?
Kostadis Roussos: takes one of his spell slots. He can't use something else as a reaction.
Daz: Okay, well then I'll go ahead and cast the same thing again. I have one more spell slot for that available, so boom.
Grygum: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you're gonna have him burn another 3rd level spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Now he has to think. Oh, but you see, there's another advantage of that. If he casts… if he casts the spell, he can't cast another spell this turn.
Kostadis Roussos: You can only cast a cantrip.
Daz: There you go.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Daz: So he has to decide whether or not he wants to be entangled and 15 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Or… or something else.
Daz: Or if he wants to… avoid that, and then cantrip me.
Daz: Or so…
Kostadis Roussos: Or do something else.
Daz: Or something else, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I mean, there's always a something else.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me just go, so, let me just…
Kostadis Roussos: What does he do?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, he will.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I need to check what his spells are. That was not what I was anticipating you to do.
Kostadis Roussos: Well done!
Kostadis Roussos: Well done.
Daz: I'm persistent.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Here's what he does.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what he does… As he casts…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… he will try his chance at this saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He spectacularly fails his saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: So he takes 15 points of damage? Is that what I'm hearing?
Daz: 15 points of damage, and he is now restrained.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: So technically, what is it called? He is… yeah, he's restrained for the duration of the spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so restrained creature's speed, and he can't move. Alright.
Daz: So… Every… every round, he can do another check to see if he can… Shake loose.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: But that uses his action.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I got it. So, here's what he does. He takes the damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Because he's a man. Actually, he's a drow, but, you know, he's a male drow.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he uses Misty Step.
Kostadis Roussos: Go over here.
Kostadis Roussos: You're standing over there, right?
Daz: I'm… I'm right here, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so he's…
Daz: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: He takes a mis… he's taking…
Daz: He can't use Misty Step, he's restrained.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you can. Restrain means your movement can't change.
Daz: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Misty Step allows you to… Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I think you can.
Daz: Hmm…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you can use Wild West Trade.
Thorin: the telephone.
Daz: Poor.
Thorin: Not… not a speed thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: But you did force him to burn one of his spells, so he can't cast a fireball, for example, or a lightning bolt.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Daz: And so he took the damage, but now… well, I can still move the hand to him, I think. Let me see how far I can move it when it's my turn again.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes. And he immediately…
Kostadis Roussos: And I have to decide who is he gonna attack.
Thorin: Right, so what happened? Give me the summary. So you…
Daz: I restrained him with a hand that came out of the ground. He took 15 points of bludgeoning damage, and then Misty stepped his ass to the other side of the room, which got him out of the hand.
Thorin: So… so he…
Daz: I wanted to avoid burning his spell list.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I wanted to avoid…
Thorin: burning his spell, and we made him burn a spell anyways, right? Yes.
Daz: He had to burn a spell, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: He had to decide which spell, like, it was either that or use a massive… so now he's forced to use…
Kostadis Roussos: a,
Kostadis Roussos: His camp trips. Alright, so he's going to use his Arcane Burst.
Kostadis Roussos: Arcane Burst. It's because that's how they've changed the spells. Alright, public.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Silly.
Kostadis Roussos: Mrs. Daz? What's your armor class, Daz?
Daz: My armor class is 12. It's not great.
Kostadis Roussos: I could only miss on a 1… on a 2… and a 1.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want you to know that. What?
Daz: And you got a 2 or a 1, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Alright. And now he hits you with a second, Arcane Burst.
Kostadis Roussos: And you take quite a bit of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Takes 26 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he turns on Zalthir and misses.
Kostadis Roussos: I think Voltaire's number one.
Thorin: an archaic.
Daz: How do you get the cats that many times?
Kostadis Roussos: They… the 5th edition Archmages were buffed to make them easier to play.
Daz: I see.
Kostadis Roussos: So they were changed. They don't have… they don't have the full flexibility of spells, but they have their…
Thorin: But I thought you said he got one spell per turn and he already burned it, or…
Kostadis Roussos: It's his cantrip.
Thorin: Oh, this is a cantrip, the arcane burst is a cantrip, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. So he has other spells, he can't cast those other spells. These are considered cantrips.
Thorin: Okay, gotcha.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want… So, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, just so that we're on the same page. They are cantrips. He does have spells, but he can't cast any of them. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Thorin: Is this, like, this can't miss, or…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I had to hit, that's… he missed… he missed…
Thorin: Oh, I see, okay, okay, the… well, where was the to-hit, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I rolled an 11 and a 16.
Thorin: Oh, okay, okay. Oh…
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled an 11 and a 25, and then a 13.
Thorin: I'm having a hard time reading these new things here, because it says Arcane Burst Range, it says Damage.
Kostadis Roussos: That's a story.
Thorin: That rolls the damage for it, got it. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So if I click the damage…
Thorin: 13 was to hit, and then you roll damage if it hits, gotcha.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
Thorin: Okay, ignore my damage, I just pressed the button that was right there.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fine, that's fine. Oh! Zalthir is in fact hit.
Kostadis Roussos: So Zalthir takes…
Kostadis Roussos: Damage.
Kostadis Roussos: 29 points of damage. Ouch, goes Zalthir.
Kostadis Roussos: How many… he's blessed, right? So he takes time. Alright.
Thorin: Yeah, what does Bless get us?
Kostadis Roussos: I guess you plus 1D4, why don't you read the description?
Grygum: Yeah, 1D4, to an attack roll, or save.
Grygum: Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target adds 1d4 to the attack roll or save.
Thorin: For everyone, okay.
Grygum: For each of the three of us, yeah.
Thorin: Boom!
Kostadis Roussos: And then… but then, after he does that, it says, He stops.
Kostadis Roussos: All four, and the boy Tadric, isn't it? I'm genuinely glad. I did not ask for him… Specifically.
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: You've been so thorough. I want that on the record before anything else happens, because I don't expect either of us will have time for compliments.
Kostadis Roussos: In the moment.
Grygum: Oh, I always have time for compliments.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… he goes, right, he goes, he goes… He pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he says.
Grygum: I mean, I also accept constructive criticism.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to ask him why he's doing anything? Like, he's… you're getting the impression that this is, like, that moment when the villain feels like.
Grygum: Oh, oh, sorry, I'm just being a smartass, but why did you feel a need to kill everybody? What, is it just megalomania?
Kostadis Roussos: anymore.
Grygum: Are you, are you trying to…
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, do you want to have your investigation tell everything, or do you want to let him say it so that you can fill in a few details that you missed out?
Grygum: Are you just trying to improve your impact factor in the journals?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… You understand me.
Grygum: Well, I was just trying to help somebody the other day get something into Archive, but I didn't know enough people who had credibility there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he goes, ju-
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, you too? Like, for a moment, he's, like, embracing for, you know, Archive is now officially canonical, a,
Grygum: I read.
Kostadis Roussos: Research, a research community.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes.
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses. He stands up, he goes, Janussi gave me 10 days! Do you understand what he was offering me? Mercy! Genuinely, he thought 10 days was kind!
Grygum: 10 days for what?
Kostadis Roussos: I have been at Candlekeep for 31 years. I do not have a house, or a family, or a country. I have a chair! He proposed to take the chair! And I found, I was surprised at this, that I would do a great deal.
Kostadis Roussos: To keep it!
Daz: So he… this is just… this is the dude with the red stapler in office space, and he snapped.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. I didn't set out to be a murderer. I didn't set out to be exiled.
Grygum: I understand now, you didn't… you were going to lose your, you know, your academic honor and privilege.
Kostadis Roussos: Right! Exactly!
Grygum: We should let this guy go. It's all justified.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you!
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you! Does anybody want to ask why he's being…
Kostadis Roussos: Like, like, you know, is this all his plot? I mean, like, he feels like he wants to…
Kostadis Roussos: You notice that there's books being stolen, right? Like, this is kind of…
Daz: This is not a common monologue for, like, a megalomaniac that's, like, is this just, like, he wants to, like, somebody left him off of, like, a citation in a paper he wrote or something? Like, he seems…
Grygum: Oh no, he's gonna lose his chair.
Daz: Yeah, that's true. So, is there anything we can do, to help you and to end this amicably without us needing to destroy you and your thugs here?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… You keep saying, I!
Kostadis Roussos: I want to accomplish then. I want to correct that, not out of modesty.
Kostadis Roussos: I have been removing books from this library for 11 years, and I have never once chosen which ones. A list arrives, I fill it. The courier who brings the list wears a glove on his right hand, and under the glove the hand is metal, and I have never in 11 years worked up the nerve to ask why.
Daz: So, there's, like.
Grygum: Who… who do you work for, then?
Kostadis Roussos: His name is Manshoon. You have not heard of it. That is not an accident. It is a career.
Grygum: Manshoon?
Thorin: Is this a multi-level marketing scheme?
Grygum: Haven't people noticed the books are missing?
Kostadis Roussos: Do you have some of that? Amazing.
Thorin: Copperware to sell us?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and so while you're kind of, like, going, roll… roll and investigate… roll a history check.
Daz: History…
Grygum: 22.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: Mystery.
Thorin: Apparently, I'm a DSO. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You immediately…
Daz: 21 also.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright, with those kinds of history checks.
Kostadis Roussos: You pause and go, but that's not possible.
Kostadis Roussos: You realize, he's talking about the Zhentarim, the Moonsea, the man who owned Zhentil Keep, a wizard who has been dead more than once.
Daz: Well, if he's been dead more than once, then maybe he's gonna be dead one more time.
Kostadis Roussos: After we're on.
Grygum: with them, sure.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… he then produces a sapphire.
Daz: Oh, is this a sapphire that you can break and the thing happens? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And he pauses. He wants one book out of this keep, and he was always going to have it. I was simply the version where nobody…
Kostadis Roussos: Had to die.
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses for a minute. It goes…
Kostadis Roussos: as he looks around and realizes that Bookwyrm's dead, and…
Kostadis Roussos: Daral almost died, and Janussi's dead, and, you know, there's the guards who died.
Kostadis Roussos: And goes, well, fewer people had to die.
Daz: do work.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: And then… He takes the sapphire and smashes it.
Grygum: I was looking for a spell that I might have to grab that sort of thing.
Daz: I have telekinesis, do I have time, like, in a reaction to grab the thing from him and pull it to me?
Daz: It's a level 5 spell, so his whole anti-spell cast thing may run in some.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, sure, we'll do that. Let's go for it.
Daz: Alright, I just casted it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you are casting it, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: So, he rolls his… so that's, 15, he has to beat a 15 to…
Daz: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, he does not!
Thorin: Huh!
Daz: And now he's restrained again. Haha!
Daz: Oh, wait, that's only if I'm holding onto him. Nevermind.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, you've cast the spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so I guess then we have to go through the whole diminishive order again. Okay, so you cast the spell, he goes, alright, so,
Daz: Okay, so he has… he has to do a strength saving throw?
Daz: And if he fails it, then I pull the object away.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Grygum: You, you have the useful spell. I wish I'd had something like that. Good job, though.
Kostadis Roussos: What do I have to roll? What is the strength check I have to roll?
Daz: Is that listed on here?
Daz: Why does it not say?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's whatever you're spelled.
Daz: This is what I'm reading. For an object, you can try to move a huge or smaller object.
Daz: If the object isn't being worn or carried, blah blah blah, doesn't apply. If the object is being worn or carried, I'm assuming it's being carried because he has it in his hand, that creature must succeed on a strength saving throw, or you pull the object away and move it up to 30 feet in any direction within the spell's range.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll… roll to, So what's your spell DC? Your spell DC is at the… right above your spell attack rolls, right next to your attack roll.
Daz: Right next to my attack roll.
Daz: Attack… Spell DC? It just says hit DC.
Daz: Scorching Ray is plus 9, I don'.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, if you go to Spells.
Daz: spells.
Daz: Okay. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: action.
Daz: Oh, Spell Attack is plus 9.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Daz: And the saved DC is 17.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's what I wanted to know.
Thorin: I don't have one of those, but I don't have a lot of spells, so…
Kostadis Roussos: You don't… do you… you can cast spells.
Thorin: All I have is Lesser Restoration, which is the… the…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah, yeah. Okay, so he gets…
Thorin: I think maybe it doesn't, show me that then.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so I have to roll… okay, so, you managed to wrench the artifact out of his hands.
Daz: Sweet.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: And… it's in my hand now.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, back to… back… back to the turn order we are!
Daz: Back to what?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so Daz, you've just rolled telekinesis and grabbed it out of his hand just before he wanted to grab it.
Kostadis Roussos: It is now in your hands.
Kostadis Roussos: There are these… there are still these two thugs over here.
Daz: So what… I forget what the rule is. If we break it, then it teleports somebody, or teleports the key directly to my hand or something? How does… what… I know we know it, I just need to look it up, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, that's the case. But let me just make sure I… yes?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that is…
Daz: And who has the other key right now? Grygum, is that right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Grygum: I've got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, you have the key. It'll take another action for you to smash it, so just keep that in mind.
Daz: They're okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You can hand it over to somebody else who can smash it, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Thorin can smash it with a wave of his… well, actually, you don't actually have, like, you know, this is one of those awkward things where you can't smash things with Dawnbringer.
Thorin: Could use the hilt, she wouldn't mind.
Daz: the experience.
Kostadis Roussos: expensive, Hiltmaster 2000?
Thorin: No, no, no, that's the case. I'm talking, like, Dawnbringer herself, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Right, right, right, right.
Thorin: I'm just saying, like, if you have a sword and you want to crack a walnut, you can just, like, smash the bottom.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, totally, totally, totally.
Thorin: Just sayin'.
Kostadis Roussos: I once went to a Ren Faire and discovered all the different ways in which a longsword could be used as a deadly weapon.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, what people think of the pointy sharp end as the dangerous parts.
Thorin: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: There's, like, 5 different other ways in which you can be badly maimed with those things.
Grygum: I mean, there's plenty of ways that you can get hurt just being careless.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. No, absolutely.
Kostadis Roussos: Absolutely. Alright. So, alright, so Daz, you have the gem in your hand.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm going to put a little circle on you so I know who has the gem. Alright.
Daz: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you stand there, or are you just gonna run down the hallway?
Daz: If… if I… if… so what's the deal? If I crush it, I get the other key?
Kostadis Roussos: You get whatever, whatever happens.
Daz: I get whatever happens.
Grygum: It triggers something, but we don't…
Daz: We don't quite know which. Okay, so I think what… and I have… let me check something.
Grygum: For all we know, it summons an elemental to kill us all.
Grygum: Kostadis is like, how'd you read? Did you read ahead?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm, I'm, okay.
Daz: I am gonna cast a cantrip.
Daz: For a minor illusion.
Daz: And while I'm doing it, I'm being flamboyant with my hand, like I'm a.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you can't. You already cast a spell, so you're… you can do… you can't cast any more spells unless they're bonus action.
Daz: Damn it.
Daz: Alright. That's a full action. Alright, what bonus action spells do I have? I'm just double checking.
Grygum: I think you… you might be able to do cantrips.
Daz: I just tried to do a cantrip. I can do Misty Step, that's a bonus action.
Daz: Which actually is not necessarily a bad idea.
Daz: Yeah, it's the only bonus action spell.
Grygum: Are you gonna run away with the key? Is that the idea?
Daz: So, I think what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna, duck back into the hallway and make it look like I'm running away, but I'm actually gonna hand Grygum the… the thing, but I'm gonna do it with, like, sleight of hand, so that somebody watching me doesn't know.
Daz: I'm gonna, like, accidentally run into Grygum, but instead of, like, pickpocketing him, actually make sure that he knows that he has the gym, because he has the other key, and that way, if the key shows up there, he'll have both.
Grygum: Good idea. Do I have to use my action to receive it?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Daz: Yeah, I could just slip it in his pocket or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you can, like, yeah, I mean, so, taking the gem and, like, it's a free action, like, you can, like, trying to break it, smash it, like, do something more than other, pass it around is a free action.
Daz: Alright, so I'm gonna… I'm gonna act like I moved over here, like I was running away with the… with the thing, but Grygum actually has it.
Grygum: That sounds like a sleight of hand check to me.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you gonna try to make it so that nobody notices?
Daz: Yeah, nobody notices, because I rolled a 19 on my sleight of hand.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay. So let me just make another note here that Grygum has the fake key.
Kostadis Roussos: Again.
Grygum: And, and the real one.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, the fake sapphire, sorry.
Grygum: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Daz: Just like…
Grygum: We already have a fake.
Daz: What? I know I give them the one I have, or is the one I have a fake one?
Grygum: No.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I was just being… I was making… I misspoke there, Daz, don't worry.
Daz: Okay, okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Grygum: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: laughing at the fact that Grygum gave Daz the fake key earlier, and now Daz is faking the sapphire to Grygum.
Daz: Right, right.
Grygum: I now have one key and one sapphire.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, exactly. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: A'lai is very upset.
Daz: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: The blank.
Thorin: Keep away.
Daz: Even better. Like, when they get upset, they make mistakes, and that's what we need.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Daz: I'm feeling pretty good that, like, my lowly little wizardry here is, like, keeping him pretty occupied.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, this is very impressive. This is very impressive.
Grygum: Okay, it looks like it's a lace right now?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I'm trying to figure out what he's gonna do. Like, I'm like, this… this was not in all the things I had planned, right?
Grygum: Did he do anything? I thought he was, stuck.
Kostadis Roussos: He can do things, yes.
Thorin: He can't move.
Thorin: He already spent his spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, he spent his spell, because he tried to control… he tried… yes, yes, yes, yes.
Thorin: You did the MISTI step, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he did the Counterspell to,
Thorin: But wasn't Misty Step a spell, too?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that was the previous round, so…
Thorin: Oh, sorry, okay, I'm…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so I'm assuming we have the dialogue here, right? And so, Daz casts a spell, A'lai's sort of sitting over there, he's now, is he looking?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. What is he going to do?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, A'lai… Decides… Steps over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And decides that he's going to…
Grygum: move.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, no, he can move.
Daz: I didn't grapple him, I grappled the thing. If I'd grappled him, he would have been restrained.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, right. So, he decides… He's a coward, so he's casting a wall of force around himself.
Kostadis Roussos: He… well, does he do that, or does he try to go… he's, like, kind of struggling with what he should do. I can't cast Wall of Forest, because he just burned all of his… he burned everything. Alright,
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at Zalthir and decides to attack Zalthir.
Grygum: world.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh my god, I can't believe I rolled so poorly.
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled two ones, I don't know whether you guys can see that.
Thorin: Yeah, but I don't know what the four of them mean. Is that damage, or is that…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's 4 attacks.
Daz: Oh, okay.
Thorin: It's 4 attacks?
Grygum: Looks like you got one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you got 2. You got 2, actually, because the plus 9 and the 18 are… the 7 plus 9 hits, so…
Kostadis Roussos: That's…
Thorin: He gets… wait, he gets 4 attacks that are plus 9?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Grygum: He's pretty high level, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: He's a very high-level wizard.
Thorin: What level is he?
Daz: Who, who took that damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Zalthir just took… Zalthir just got knocked out.
Daz: Oh, damn.
Daz: That's my bad.
Daz: I was a little bitch and grabbed the sapphire and then ran away.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so Zalthir is knocked out.
Kostadis Roussos: Fortunately, Zalthir is not here to correct me with all of the caveats.
Daz: I'm sure he has.
Kostadis Roussos: At this point in time, at this point in time, I want… just for the historical record, Zalthir would have figured out how to sleazebag himself out of this, and so…
Daz: Yeah. If there's a safe… if there's a safe.
Grygum: Throw Bless Hopes.
Kostadis Roussos: No, there's not. He's… okay. So…
Kostadis Roussos: And I like Aivenmore, kind of, like.
Kostadis Roussos: Tries to hide himself, sort of, behind the, behind the, the bookshelf.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Thorin, you're up.
Thorin: Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: There's these two thugs that are standing there, ready to be terrifyingly into me.
Thorin: So I know our original plan was that I was gonna fight the thugs. I don't think I can get…
Kostadis Roussos: That's a bookshelf, by the way.
Thorin: Oh, so I'd have to go around and…
Kostadis Roussos: It could take an attack of opportunity, you don't… there's nothing…
Thorin: What's that?
Kostadis Roussos: Walk past them, you can…
Thorin: Yeah, it's like, I… I mean, I can do 30…
Thorin: And I don't think I have anything that'll get me moving faster than that.
Thorin: So I think what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna…
Thorin: try and actually just take out the thugs, because I don't want them sort of creating chaos. What do you guys think?
Grygum: I… that… that's reasonable.
Thorin: Yeah, I wish I could do something for Zalthir, but I don't think there's anything practically I can do from here.
Grygum: I, I can, I can help him after the fight.
Kostadis Roussos: Also, Glabbagool's on top of him, so Glabbagool could always help him.
Thorin: Alright, so I'm gonna move…
Kostadis Roussos: I can stabilize them from dying, so…
Thorin: I'm gonna move here, and then we're.
Kostadis Roussos: Agreed.
Thorin: Brian, take out…
Kostadis Roussos: Glabbagool has to go all, you know, ballistic.
Thorin: 21…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's a hit, that's a hit.
Thorin: 21 points of damage. Oh, wait, no, that's against Undead, so it's…
Thorin: 13 points of damage, I think.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thorin: Because it's not undead, they're not undead, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, they're not undead. Very much not undead.
Thorin: And then wait, can I do something?
Kostadis Roussos: Can I just say something? They improved the performance of the blood splatter.
Daz: I mean.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know whether you noticed that, whenever you cause damage, you see the funnel of blood pops up.
Grygum: It's, it's good that they focus on the important things.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, dude, like, that's the important stuff, like, it's like customer love. Alright.
Thorin: Wait, I want to figure out what I want to do next. Here, give me a second.
Thorin: What do I have? I can do… I don't want to waste too much on these guys, so…
Thorin: Just trying to figure out if I want to do anything super special.
Thorin: Okay, so I have a superiority die.
Thorin: which I can use for maneuvers.
Thorin: And…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and as you're looking at them, you realize that these guys work for the Zhentarim.
Thorin: Oh, okay.
Thorin: The problem is that this page of, like, abilities is so freaking long that it's hard to figure out what's what.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, my son says he wants the character trait where you optimize your character and then just press a button so you don't have to think what you're gonna do in the middle of combat.
Thorin: I know, right? Okay. I bet Claude can do that. I'm gonna do a menacing attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thorin: Which gives me a…
Thorin: Which I… okay, so superiority dies, which are down here, which are where… I don't even frickin' know, where are they on this thing? I'm scrolling around.
Thorin: Alright.
Thorin: Does give me a 1D8 that adds damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Grygum: Wow.
Thorin: So, 3, another 3… And then,
Thorin: Dude has to beat a DC… 16?
Kostadis Roussos: He did.
Thorin: Well, damn it.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he's, you know, he's the thug, like, you know, he's a… He's a Zhentarim thug.
Thorin: Or DC16 Wisdom. Okay, so… Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You got… that was your first attack, you get two attacks.
Thorin: Yeah, yeah, I get another attack here.
Kostadis Roussos: SAP, I believe, is what the… gives the other… gives you advantage on the second?
Thorin: So, another 8.
Thorin: And then… then he gets disadvantage on his next attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that's what it does.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Grygum, you're up.
Thorin: able to do, like, more attacks, this is the thing. It's like, I just…
Thorin: I don't miss, but also I need to be able to just pound.
Kostadis Roussos: Right away.
Grygum: So, I am going to, charge forward here, and then, cast,
Grygum: Tasha's Caustic Brew, attempting to get to both of the thugs.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, both of the thugs, okay, go for it.
Grygum: So, let's see… They need to get us a 17 dexterity save to avoid, getting covered.
Kostadis Roussos: They blow both of their saving throws.
Grygum: Okay, then at the start of each of their turns, until they, scrape it.
Grygum: scrape it off, they take 2 die 4 damage. Oh, this is a concentration spell, so I think I have to end the blessing.
Thorin: We're gonna be right back. I'm gonna hit the restroom. Are we… are we almost done?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, we're almost done. This is, so roll for… roll for damage?
Grygum: It starts… it's at the start of their turns.
Kostadis Roussos: Start of their turns. Alright, well, it is the start of their turn, so… 2d4's worth of damage.
Grygum: Okay.
Grygum: Then… let me do that.
Grygum: 8 on one of them.
Kostadis Roussos: He dies.
Grygum: And 2 on the other.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and we will stop here.
Thorin: Alright, thank you guys.
Kostadis Roussos: And we will have, let me just make a note here,
Kostadis Roussos: I need to add a note here that, I mean, we can drop off, I just need to note that…
Kostadis Roussos: grab a goal needs to go.
Grygum: Oh, okay.
Daz: That's honest.
Grygum: I will note that they're covered in acid.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Take care. It was fun.
Grygum: Goodbye.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, so how's the ha.